Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 91.
We are going to implement the breadth first search algorithm and Java, so I will create a graph and
the fall in the next couple of minutes in the codes.
So this graph it will contain four vertices is it starts from zero, one, two and three.
And this graph zero is connected to one zero is connected to two and two and one is connected to to
do connected two zero, two connected to three and three connected to three.
So three is connected to three.
It is a loop looping and directing to itself.
OK, so the the b f as.
Of this graph will be calculated, and this bled into the council and the following exercise.
So let's begin creating the beef's algorithm and job.
We open our intelligence or your any Java compiler.
We go to the source code and we create a new Java class iris called B f s graph.
OK.
This is a new Java class.
And by the way, you can download all of these source codes from the Resources folder and on Udemy course.
OK.
And that link below.
So I will create private and v and the private LinkedIn list linkage list it took and you can specify
the integer and Jason's, and we are going to implement it and enter to add the Java Digital Dot drink
at last.
So we are adding from the Java Collection framework, a link list and we name it as adjacent and array.
So I will create that graph by by creating the constructor.
So create a graph b f as a graph.
It took into the parameter and v so I put I should put this b small ledger and this v equal to V and
adjacent, adjacent, equal to new link list.
And I specify the starting point of this link, at least from V and the index of this link atlas that
v.
So by making a for loop and I equal to zero, we start from zero.
We and at the I list them fear and I + +.
OK.
We looked through all the elements from zero two v no adjacent at index v a dot and what we are going
to add.
So not we are going to add we are going to create a new link at least.
And this.
OK.
So for that, everything is working fine.
Now let's make a new method that at the edges.
So think their edges.
We start by ad void, AB Edge and we start by passing two parameters that vertex and the end W.
So what to do?
We are going to add adjacent at index fee and add the and W.
OK.
So this is very simple addition for the edge we have seen in the previous videos and we have created
it in.
Now let's concentrate on the main purpose of this exercise is to be after us.
Algo great.
OK.
So Boolean visited array equal to new Boolean as a and I passed V.
Okay, so that this means that we have visited the vertex and this has very logic because we start from
the vertex.
So the starting point is visited because we have started from it.
So I will create the link atlas of and preserve parameter type called the Q Equals to new link atlas.
We have implemented this exercise in in C and a different way.
We have created a Q Q and this exercise.
We are going to work with that link at least, so I will create the f visited visited.
This method, I need to make it in the method, sorry.
Here I have messed up or void the IFRS integers.
And as I took into the parameter in S and here visited
visited at Index S equal to the rule and the Q, this is a linked list, but I prefer naming it as a
Q because this algorithm works as the basics of the Q and a bit on the basics of the Q.
So while you thought you thought size does not equal to zero.
What we need to do, we are going to add s equal to Q Dot Ball.
And since then, the system took out dot print.
As a plus in the space they are pulling, no.
Let's make the iterator that goes through all of this data.
Iterator at end of time and to share the perimeter I equals to adjacent.
And indexed the list, the list is the writer, OK, so we are making it as illustrate why I don't have
next.
OK, if I has next, then I will create end and equal to I dot next.
OK.
And if it does not equal to visited or the visit does not return it true, then this visit that Saturday
at index and equal to true.
OK, so while visit that does not contain and.
And next and then make visit that and equal to true and the Q Good.
And this will specify for us that this index and has been visited and we have added correctly to that
visit that method and the visit the array that correct the visit, that vertex.
OK, so.
Let's test our code and the main method, so public.
We need tested here.
Public static void main
stream args and we start by making it creating a depth and breadth and breadth first.
Search graph g equal to you breath and having bird kisses.
As for now, let's add what we have created at the beginning of the video that graph that we have shown.
And so I had the edges.
I would copy this.
OK, so I will connect zero was one zero was to Irish Connect.
One with two iconic do was zero.
And I will connect do with three, and I will connect the city by itself, by itself.
OK, now I will train system to get the out good print.
The following
is the
breadth the first traversal.
OK.
Gee, don't we call the Method B asked us and we pass the starting point is to I would start from zero
not to.
OK, so I will run this example run.
OK.
Let me check it again around the graph, and we have some error.
Let me see.
OK, I have missed this adjacent at the end.
I'm not me.
That's wrong, Nancy.
And here we go.
We have zero, one, two and three.
This is the breadth B as traversal of the previously created.